Medbh McGuckian papers, 1964-2006
Emory University
- Printed material, Series 5; Box 48: Folder 4 - Box 71, OP 5-22
  - Writings by Medbh McGuckian, Subseries 5.1; Box 48: Folder 4 - Box 56a: Folder 3; OP5
    - "The Roofspace" in Ulster Tatler, November 1979, p. 51 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - "The Flitting" in The Listener, 20 and 27 December 1979, p 871 [2 copies] (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - "The Retired Couple" and "Hibernia" in London Magazine, December 1979/January 1980, pp. 114-115 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - "Winter," "The Black Nun" and "The Fire-Dance" in Cyphers, Spring 1980, pp. 34-35 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - "The Sun-Trap" in Outposts, Summer 1980, p. 16 [This periodical includes an untitled manuscript poem by McGuckian on the back of the front cover. The poem opens: "As I passed the green world..."] (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - "Gentians" in Fortnight, October-November 1980, p. 21 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - "The Love Game" and "Gate Posts" in Threshold, Autumn/Winter 1980, p. 9 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - "The Milk Cap" in Poetry Review, December 1980, p. 13 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - "Collusion," "Work," "The Night-Mirror," and "The Charm School" in Aquarius, 1980, pp. 48-49 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - "Choosing," "Phases" and "The Grand Mountain Hotel" in Green River Review, 1980, pp. 54-55 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - "Underground" in The Connacht Tribune, January 1, 1981, p 10 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - "The Moon-Shell," "Next Day Hill," "The Standing," "Wonderland" in Bananas, February-March [1981], pages 14-15 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - "The Sea-Wood" and "The Window" in The Poetry Ireland Review, Winter 1981, p. 29 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - "Driving" and "Fishing" in The Connacht Tribune, 1 May 1981, p 18. (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - "The Aphrodisiac" and "The Flower Master" in The Honest Ulsterman, November-December 1981, p. 16-17 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - "The Sitting" and "The Heiress" in New Statesman, 11 December 1981, p. 18 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - "The Soil-Map" in Poetry Supplement (Compiled by Andrew Motion for the Poetry Book Society), Christmas '81 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - "Aunts," "Waterford," "Garam masala," "Those People," "Poison," "My mother," " Gateposts," "That Year," "The House," "June," "The glory-hole," "Chopping," "The moonbow," "The thorough bed," "Winter," "Prudence," "The Strike," "Smoke," "The Folk Museum," and "Collusion" in Trio Poetry 2, 1981, pp. 25-44 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - "The Frame" and "The Villian" in The Connacht Tribune, April 30 1982, p. 20 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - "The Artemesia" in Poetry Review, June 1982, p. 12 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - "Ode to a Poetess," in A Tribute to William Wiser, Writer in residence at The Queen's University of Belfast, 1979-1982, pp. 8-9 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - "The Nightworker" in The Belfast Review, [1982], page 34 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - "Goya" in Outposts, Spring 1983, p. 17 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - "For the Previous Owner" and "The Last Days of Pisces" in Ulster Tatler, June 1983, p. 45 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - "Blue Vase" in The Belfast Review, Summer 1983, p. 33 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - "The Throne" in Outposts, Summer 1983, p. 20 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - "Losing," "Underground," "The Trough," and "A Change of Place" in Poetry Review, September 1983, pp. 17-18 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - "Venus and the Sun" in Outposts, Autumn 1983, p. 33 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - "Staying in a Better Hotel" in New Statesman, 30 December 1983, p. 20 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - "Rowing" in Aquarius XV/XVII, 1983/1984, p. 74 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - "Valentina" in New Statesman, 10 February 1984, p. 24 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - "Too Much Yellow," " The Grayling," "January," "The Villa," and "The Bone-Setter" in London Review of Books, 7 June to 20 June 1984, p. 6 [2 copies] (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - "Never," "The Sailor" and "The Golden Path" in Cyphers, Summer 1984, pp. 30-31 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - "Felicia's Cafe," "The Colouring Book" and "Four O'Clock, Summer Street" in Poetry Ireland Review, Autumn 1984, pp. 7-8 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - "Before the Wedding" in Poetry Supplement, 1984, Winter 1984, p. 25 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - "Minus 18 Street" and 5 poems without English titles translated into Dutch in Poesi Magasin, 1984, pp. 22-24 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - "Grainne's Sleep Song" and "Lucina" in Hubbub, Spring 1985, pps 38-39 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - "Sea or Sky" in The New Yorker, 24 June 1985, p. 38 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - "The Frame" in Poetry Canada Review, Summer 1985, p. 42 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - "The Sailor" in Outposts, Summer 1985, p. 7 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - "Ylang-Ylang" in Poetry, July 1985, p. 203 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - "Aunt Dorothy's Tale" in Outposts, Autumn 1985, p. 15 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - "Children of the Mist" and "The Fire Tower" in Poetry Canada Review, Autumn 1985, p. 6 [2 copies] (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - "What Does 'Early' Mean?" and "Mrs. Orchard" in The Honest Ulsterman, Autumn 1985, pp. 7-8 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - "The Nightworker," "Makings," and "Work" in Poetry Review, October 1985, pp. 4-5 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - "The Aphrodisiac," "The Sun-Trap" and "Gentians" in Edward Lucie-Smith, Ed., British Poetry Since 1945, Penguin Books, 1985, pp.366-368 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - "Coleridge" and "April" in Gown Literary Supplement, 1985, p. 15 [4 copies] (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - "My Brown Guest," "Moonshots," "Little House, Big House," "The Difficult Age," "Querencia," and "Poem for a Lost Birthday" in Robin Robertson, Ed., Firebird 4, Penguin Books, 1985, pp. 185-192 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - "Grainne's Sleep Song" and "Lucina" in Hubbub, 1985, pp. 38-39 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - "Dancing" and "Mazurka" in Poetry Australia, 1985, pp. 44-45 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - "Coleridge" in Poetry Durham, Summer 1986, p. 17 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - "Problem Girl" in Struga International Poetry Review, August 1986, p. 27. (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - "On Ballycastle Beach," "The Stone-Hitter," Suivez Moi," and "To a Cuckoo at Coolnalough" in Verse, 1986, pp. 27-28 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - "The Dolphin" in Poets for Africa, 1986, p. 32 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - "Woman with Blue-Ringed Bowl," "Jazzmen Say Head" and "Martini Terrace" in The Salmon, Winter 1987 pp. 10-12 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - "The Time Before You" and "First Letters from a Steamer" in North, Winter/Spring 1987, pp. 18-19 [3 copies] (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - "Echo-Poem" in Maryland Poetry Review, Spring/Summer 1987, p. 24 [2 copies] (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - "Amelia" in Four Quarters, Fall 1987, p. 58 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - "Head of a Woman," "The Invalid's Echo," "To Call Paula Paul," and "Girl-Mother and Child" in The Irish Review, 1987, pp. 72-78 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - "Problem Girl," "The Sofa," "To My Grandmother," "Hotel," "Lychees," "The Mirror" and "From Disciple to Master" (in English with French translation on facing page); and article "Interview with Medbh McGuckian" in Cahiers Sur La Poesie, 1987, pp. 181-201 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Poem translated into Dutch in Lyrikvannen, 1987, p. 162 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - "Adonis Dark" in Gown Literary Supplement, 1987, p. 27 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - "Dear Rain.," "Mrs. Orchard" and "Head of a Woman" in Antaeus, Spring 1988, pp. 198-202 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - "Anna's Lane," "Displaced to the Blue," "Garbo at the Gaumont," and "Gigot Sleeves" in Oxford Poetry, Spring 1988, pp14-17 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - "The Lemon Shed" and "Shaferi" in Orbis, Summer/Autumn 1988, pp. 42-43 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - German translations "An Meine Grossmutter" and "Die Sitzung" in Die Horen, 3rd Quarter, 1988, p. 174 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - "In the Day Room" and "A Dream of Stone" and article "Body Logic: Some Notes on the Poetry of Medbh McGuckian" in Gown Literary Supplement, 1988, pp. 4, 7, 16-18 [2 copies] (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - "Living Beyond a Window" in The Simon Anthology of Poetry, 1988, p. 50 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - "To Call Paula Paul," "Martini Terrace," "Petite Maison," "Scenes From a Brothel," "To the Oak-Leaf Camps," and "What Does 'Early' Mean?" in Prospice, 1988, pp. 227-234 [2 copies] (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Dutch translations "De Sofa," "Chemiestraat," "De moord om de bruidsschat," "Het Hollywood-bed," "Aan de nachtegaal," "Ondergrondse," and "Prie-Dieu" in Het dwingende verleden, 1988, pp. 104-108 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - "Anna's Lane," "Zero Eighteen," "Sword-Sonnets," "Cancelleresca Bastarda," "The Cutting-Out Room," "The Moses Room," "Drawing Ballerinas" and "Gigot Sleeves" in Todd Swift and Martin Mooney, Eds., Map-Makers' Colours: New Poets of Northern Ireland, Nu-Age Editions, 1988, pp. 17-29 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - "Shifting Flats" and "Tiled Bathroom" in Cimarron Review, January 1989, pp. 30-31 [2 copies] (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - "The Keeper Ring"and "Two Heliotropes" in Gown Literary Supplement, January 1989, p. 3 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - "View Without a Room" and "A Dream of Stone" in Stand, Summer 1989, pp. 12-13 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - "The Cloth Mother" and "The Book Room" in The Poetry Book Society Anthology, 1988-1989, pp. 65-66 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - "The Invalid's Echo" in Visions, 1989 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - "Living Beyond a Window," "A Different Same," "Reading in a Library," "Dormer Window," "Clotho," "The Dead Are More Alive," "The Voice Coach," "Snuff," and "The Watchfire" in Rhinoceros, 1989, pp. 17-28 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - "Zero Eighteen" and "Whimbrel" in Passages North, Winter 1990, pages 27-29 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - "The Rosary Dress," "Cancelleresca Bastarda" and "Journal Intime" in Pearl, Fall 1990, pages 2-4 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Swedish [?] translations "Min Mor," "Hacka Lok," "Rok," "Sabbath Park," and "Fergus och hans drommars sprak" in Fardvag, 1990, pages 143-147 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Dutch translations "Het Ongeluk," "Geloof," "Gezinsplanning," and "Harembroek" in Ik heb tien benen, 1990, pages 98-102 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - "The Moses Room" and "Aquarelle" in Living Landscape Anthology, 1990, pages 21-22 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - "Cancelleresca Bastarda" in Confounded Language, Bloodaxe Books, 1991, page 19 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - "Power-Cut," "The Butterfly Farm," "Your House," "Ducks and Drakes," "Rowing," "Freeze-Up," "On Not Being Listened To," "Through the Round Window," For a Young Matron," and "A Conversation Set to Flowers" with facing-page French translations in Poetes D'Irlande du Nord, Amiot Lenganey, 1991, pages 153-167 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - "The Orchid House," "To My Grandmother," "That Year," "Admiring the Furs," and "Tulips" with facing-page German translations in Flugasche, Winter 1992, pages 41-42 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - "Dream in a Train" in Quarto, 1992, page 28 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - "Answering the Daffodils" in Mna na hEorpa: Women of Europe, A Celebration by Irish Women Poets, 1992 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - "Story Between Two Notes" and "Speaking Into the Candles" in Michigan Quarterly Review, Winter 1993, pages 128-131 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - "Red Trial" in Flaming Arrows, 1993, pages 10-11 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - "The Tomorrow Club" in untitled, privately published book of poems in honor of the 60th birthday of James Simmons, 1993 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Romanian [?] translations "Journal Intime," "Fata Problema," "Scene Dintr-Un Bordel," "Felicia's Cafe," "Ferma de Fluturi," and "Omul Care Vine Joi" in Poesis, 1993, page 24 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - "Six Poems, offprints from Common Knowledge, including the poems "Breaking the Blue," "Dear Rain," "Almond," "Soliloquy to a Cloud," "The Carrying Ring," and "At Mullaghmore" [circa 1993] (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - "The Chamomile Lawn" in Shivaun O'Casey's The Plough and the Stars program [circa 1993] (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - "The Colony Room" in The Spark, June 1994, page 38 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - "Skull Light," "The Albert Chain," "Waxwing Winter," "The Nearness of the Grape Arbour to the Fruit Cellar" in The American Voice, 1994, pages. 33-38 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - "Timed Chess" on Trinity Poetry Broadsheet, 1994 (Box OP5)
    - "Black Virgin," "Dividing the Political Temperature," "White Windsor Soap" in Epoch, 1995, pages 264-268 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - "The Field of Nonduality," "More than a Letter," "Impressionist House" in Tabla, 1995, pages 16-18 [includes ALS, 10 May 1995, from Stephen Ellis] (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "Venus and the Rain" in Kilkenny People, 1995, page 49 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - "The Surrender Dance," "Filming the Famine," and "A Perfume Called 'My Own,'" in Sibila, January 1996, pages 3-4 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "The Third Chessplayer" in Asylum: Arts Review, Winter 1996, page 8 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - "Mating with the Well" and "The Tamarind Tree" in Compost, Spring 1996, pages 14-15 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - "Filming the Famine" and "The Jasmine-Picker" in Chicago Review, Winter 1997, pages 1-4 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - "Bond" and "Gate of Heaven" [translations of Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill's "Geasa" and "Toircheas 2"] in Bonded Shores, May 1997, pages 2 and 5 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - "The Feminine Christs," "The Building of the 'Hebe,'" "Locust in the Cemetery" in Verse, 1997, pages 87-89 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - "Green Crucifix" in Ceide, January/February 1998, page 36 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - "Night When One Hears the Sea Without Seeing It," "Making Your Own Eclipse," "Four Studies of Her Right Breast" in PN Review, November-December 1999, pages 28-30 (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - "Birthday Composition of Horses," "From a Young Girl to an Old Woman," and "Corduroy Road" in Verse, 1999, pages 28-31 (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - "Image of Migratory Cranes," "Ring Worn Outside a Glove," "The Finisher" in Ropes, 1999, pages 29-30 (Box 55a, Folder 1)
    - "Josephine," "A Cura de Sona," "Lapsos," "Lichias," "Fe," and "A 'Singer'" in Poesia em Lisboa 99, 1999, pages 79-85 [2 copies] (Box 55a, Folder 2)
    - "Statt Bronze Keramik and Holz" ["Ceramic and Wood for Bronze"] in Die Horen, 2000, page 192 (Box 55a, Folder 3)
    - "Clara-Motiv" ["Clara Theme"] in Die Horen, 2001, pages 213-214 (Box 55a, Folder 4)
    - "Santo Spirito" in the Times Literary Supplement, 6 February 2004, page 5 (Box 55a, Folder 5)
    - "The Angel Musician" in the Times Literary Supplement, 2 April 2004, page 11 (Box 55a, Folder 6)
    - "Soul Being Saved by an Angel" in the Times Literary Supplement, 4 June 2004, page 15 (Box 55a, Folder 7)
    - "The Stone-word" and "Regaining Control of the Night" in Eureka Street, September-October 2005, pages 19 and 25 (Box 55a, Folder 8)
    - "Ales Stenar" and "At Mullaghmore" in The Honest Ulsterman, undated, pages 10-11 (Box 55a, Folder 9)
    - "The Daisy Cutter" and "The Fashion Parade" in Tangier, undated, pages 14-15 (Box 55a, Folder 10)
    - "The Rising Out" in Pequod, Number 16/17, undated, page 44 (Box 55a, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous xeroxes of printed poems (Box 55a, Folder 12)
    - Publications with prose and interviews
    - Review of John Hewitt's The Rain Dance and Wes Magee's No Man's Land in Northern Lights, April 1979, p. 23 (Box 55a, Folder 13)
    - "Gardner Outside the Walls" [review of Francis Stuart's We Have Kept the Faith], 12 June 1982 (Box 55a, Folder 14)
    - "Subjective Correlatives" [review of John Montague and Ted Hughes' Selected Poems], 10 July 1982 (Box 55a, Folder 15)
    - "The Best Poetry Books of Our Time" in Poetry Review, April 1984, page 43 (Box 55a, Folder 16)
    - "Mystical Island in a Dusky Bay" [review of Liam Blake's Real Ireland: People and Landscape in Fortnight], December 1984, page 23 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - "Bawling across the hearthrug" [article on Irish poetry] in Books and Bookmen, March 1986, page 23-24 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - "Skrimshadering, or not the Rupert Bear School" [article on poetry and politics] in Books and Bookmen, July 1986, page 22 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - "The Mutiny of Selves: An Interview with Medbh McGuckian" in Cencrastus, Spring 1988, pages 17-21 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - "The Light of the Penurious Moon" [review of Rita Ann Higgins's Goddess on the Mervue Bus in The Honest Ulsterman], Summer 1988, pages 60-62 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - "On Ballycastle Beach: Medbh McGuckian on her "Diary'" in The Poetry Book Society Bulletin, Summer 1988, page 10 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - "To Pour is to Fill" [review of Lionel Shriver's The Female of the Species in The Honest Ulsterman], Summer 1988, p. 63-66 [See Subseries 5.1, Printed Material, Writings by McGuckian: "The Light of the Penurious Moon"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Stripping off the Masks" [review of BBC documentary "Cast a Cold Eye" based on Richard Ellman's biography of Yeats], in Fortnight, March 1989, page VI [2 copies] (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Brief letter indicating Emily Bronte's poem "No Coward Soul is Mine" as her favorite poem, in Lifelines III, 1990, page 14 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - "Visiting Poet" in The Irish Review, Winter 1991/1992, page 47 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - "Clear Conscience" [McGuckian interviews Carol Rumens] in Fortnight, January 1993, pages 48-49 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Untitled review of John Booths' Jack B. Yeats: A Vision of Ireland in Fortnight, February 1994, pages 47-48 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Contribution to "Varieties of Irishness?" in Fortnight, March 1994, pages 39-40 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - "Is That a Dove I See?" in The Independent, 2 September 1994, page 19 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Review of Word of Mouth ed. Ruth Carr, Grainne Tobin, Sally Wheeler, and Ann Zell, in Causeway, Winter 1996, page 58 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - "Who Was Who?" [review of Anne Ulry Colman's A Dictionary of 19th Century Irish Women Poets in Irish Journal of Feminist Studies], December 1997, pages 111-113 (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - "The Culture of Poetry in Ireland" in Ropes, 1997, page 64 [2 copies] (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - "The Seal Woman" [review of Moyra Donaldson's Snakeskin Stilettos] in Fortnight, March 1999, pages 27-28 (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Interview with Vona Groarke in Verse, 1999, pages 32-43 [See Subseries 5.1, Printed Material, Writings by McGuckian, Publications with Poems, "Birthday Composition of Horses," "From a Young Girl to an Old Woman," and "Corduroy Road" in Verse, 1999, pages 28-31] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Interview in Ulster Tatler, May 2001, pages 22-24 (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Off-prints of article "Birds and Their Masters" [review of Eavan Boland's poetry] (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - Many off-prints of article "How Precious Also Are Thy Thoughts Unto Me" [review of Marina Tsvetaeva's poetry] from Common Knowledge (Box 56a, Folder 1)
    - Publications for which McGuckian served as Editor
    - Gown Literary Supplement, Autumn/Winter 1989 (Box 56a, Folder 2)
    - Gown Literary Supplement, Spring/Summer 1990 (Box 56a, Folder 3)
  - Writings about Medbh McGuckian, Subseries 5.2; Box 56a: Folder 4 - Box 60; OP 6-15, 29-30
    - Reviews
    - Single Ladies (Box 56a, Folder 4)
    - Portrait of Joanna (Box 56a, Folder 5)
    - Trio Poetry 2 (Box 56a, Folder 6)
    - The Flower Master (Box 56a, Folder 7)
    - The Flower Master [See also Subseries 5.1, Printed Material, Writings by McGuckian, Publications with Poems, "The Nightworker" in The Belfast Review, [1982]] (Box 56a, Folder 8)
    - Venus and the Rain (Box 56a, Folder 9)
    - On Ballycastle Beach [See also Subseries 5.1, Printed Material, Writings by McGuckian, Publications with Poems, "Zero Eighteen and Whimbrel" in Passages North] (Box 56a, Folder 10)
    - Marconi's Cottage (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Captain Lavender (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Selected Poems (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Shelmalier [See also Subseries 5.1, Printed Material, Writings by McGuckian, Publications with Poems, "Birthday Composition of Horses," "From a Young Girl to an Old Woman," and "Corduroy Road" in Verse, 1999, and Subseries 5.1, Printed Material, Writings by McGuckian, Publications with Prose and Interviews, "The Seal Woman" in Fortnight, March 1999] (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - The Face of the Earth (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - The Soldiers of Year II (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Had I a Thousand Lives (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - The Younger Irish Poets (1982), Ed. Gerald Dawe, in Ulster Tatler, October 1982, p. 92 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - The Female Line: Northern Irish Women Writers (1985) (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - The Wake Forest Book of Irish Women's Poetry (1999), edited by Peggy O'Brien (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - The Water Horse (2000) by Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill with translations by Medbh McGuckian and Eiléan Ní Chuilleanáin (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Profiles and promotional items
    - Newspaper clippings: news, profiles and general reviews of McGuckian, 1979-1980 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper clippings: news, profiles and general reviews of McGuckian, 1981-1982 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper clippings: news, profiles and general reviews of McGuckian, 1983-1986 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings: news, profiles and general reviews of McGuckian, 1987-1990 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings: news, profiles and general reviews of McGuckian, 1993-2005 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings: news, profiles and general reviews of McGuckian, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Brief profile of McGuckian in Image, January 1983, page 44 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - "The Ulster Renaissance" in Newsweek, 12 May 1986, pages 52-54 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Today and Yesterday, BBC Radio for Schools, Autumn term 1986, pages 21-24 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Interview in Gown Literary Supplement, 1986, pages15-18 [2 copies] (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Article "Why Poetess?" briefly touches upon McGuckian, in The Linen Hall Review, Autumn 1987, pages 8-9 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - "Initiations, Tempers, Seductions: The Postmodern McGuckian," by Thomas Docherty in The Chosen Ground: Essays on the Contemporary Poetry of Northern Ireland, edited by Neil Corcoran, 1992 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - "An Interview with Medbh McGuckian" by Susan Shaw Sailer in Michigan Quarterly Review, Winter 1993, pps 111-127 [See Subseries 5.1, Printed Material, Writings about McGuckian: "Story Between Two Notes" and "Speaking Into the Candles" in Michigan Quarterly Review, Winter 1993] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "'Rising Out': Medbh McGuckian's Destabilizing Poetics" in Eire - Ireland, Winter 1996, pages 154-172 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - "Feminist Recovery Work and Women's Poetry in Ireland" by Spurgeon Thompson in Irish Journal of Feminist Studies, December 1997, pages 94-105 [See Subseries 5.1, Printed Material, Writings by McGuckian: " Who was Who?" in Irish Journal of Feminist Studies, December 1997] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Erzählt sie weiter, unsere Geschichten!: Zwei Irinnen ein Ire in der Gastpoeten-Reihe" ["Keep telling our stories! Two Irishwomen and one Irishman in the Guest Poet Series"] by Inés Gutiérrez in UniPress, February 1998, pages 52-53 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - "Medbh McGuckian" by Jens Koch, [circa 1998] (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - "Ireland's Best" by Kate Daniels in The Southern Review, Spring 1999, pages 387-402 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Profile of McGuckian in Eureka Irish Poetry Special Issue [Japanese language publication], February 2000, pages 106-107 [includes ALS, n.d., unsigned] (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - "Both Flower and Flower Gatherer: Medbh McGuckian's The Flower Master and H.D.'s Sea Garden" by Lesley Wheeler in Twentieth-Century Literature, Winter 2003 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - "'Because God is forbidden to perform miracles in this place': Medbh McGuckian's Sense of History" by María Jesús Lorenzo Modia in Thistles, 2005 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - "Angels Among Us: Medbh McGuckian's Recent Poems" by María Jesús Lorenzo Modia in Ireland in the Coming Time, 2006 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - "An Attitude of Compassions: Q & A with Medbh McGuckian" by Kathleen McCracken, undated (Box 59, Folder 8)